Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn letterhead collection
1802-2002
1850-1970
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0008
8.3 Linear Feet in 24 binder boxes
The Brooklyn letterhead collection spans 200 years of business in Brooklyn. Several thousand different businesses, institutions, and organizations are represented in the collection, including carpenters, plumbers, painters, city agencies, religious institutions, and more.
Box A
Box Ba-Bn
Box Bo-Bz
Box Brooklyn
Box Ca-Coh
Box Col-Cu
Box D
Box E
Box F
Box G
Box Ha-Hi
Box Ho-I
Box J
Box K
Box L
Box Ma-Me
Box Mi-My
Box N-O
Box P-Q
Box R
Box Sa-Sh
Box Si-Sz
Box T, U, V
Box Wa-Wie
Box Wil-X, Y, Z
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection is a compendium of smaller collections and individual items from various sources and will continue to grow.
Arrangement
The items are arranged alphabetically by business name. Multiple items from the same business are arranged chronologically.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection has been completely digitized, but is not yet available online. Consult CBH staff for more information.
Related Materials
Brooklyn ephemera collection (BCMS.0007)
Brooklyn Historical Society ephemera collection (ARC.272)
Abraham & Straus collection (ARC.223)
Brooklyn business blotters (BCMS.0097)
Checks and receipts from Brooklyn businesses and institutions collection (CBHM.0014)
Brooklyn and New York City business catalogs collection (1986.047)
Brooklyn Newsstand: Our digital and keyword-searchable database of over 40 local Brooklyn newspapers includes advertisements for, articles mentioning, and sometimes even images of the businesses in this collection.
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn letterhead collection spans 200 years of business in Brooklyn. Several thousand different businesses, institutions, and organizations are represented in the collection, including carpenters, plumbers, painters, city agencies, religious institutions, and more. The complete listing of the names, addresses, and dates from the letterhead collection could be used by genealogical researchers, those interested in the history of various industries in Brooklyn, neighborhood historians and many others. Many of the letterheads are visually interesting as well, with elaborate typefaces, intricate imagery, and archaic handwriting.
Industries -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- History; New York (N.Y.) -- Officials and employees; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Politics and government; Business; Business enterprises -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Business enterprises -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- History; Business records; Letterheads; Stationery; Abraham & Straus; Namm's (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Frederick Loeser Co
- A-J Letter Service, circa early 1900s
  Scope and Contents
  Printing and mailing. 1314 Avenue M
- Abbott Brewing Co., The, 1886
  Brewery. Cor. Bushwick Avenue, Meserole & Scholes Sts
- Abbott & Co, 1869
  Brewery. 9 Court Street
- Abbott, W.G., 1888
  Brewer of ales, porter and lager beer. Bushwick Ave and Meserole St.
- Abraham & Straus, 1894, 1897, 1899, 1918, 1939, 1956
  Department store. Fulton Street at Hoyt
- Abrams, J.T., 1936, 1940
  Licensed electrical contractor. 2041 Flatbush Avenue; 2055 Flatbush Avenue
- Abt, John, 1878, 1895
  Locksmith and bell hanger. 208, 268, 269 Flatbush Ave
- Ace Chromium & Nickel Plating Works
  Metal plating works. 1793 Nostrand Avenue
- Ace Plumbing Co., Inc., 1939
  Plumbing and heating. 2507 Surf Avenue
- Ackerman, H.B.'s Son, 1883
  Coal and wood dealer. Yard cor. Fulton and Waverly Aves
- Ackley, James, 1890
  Carpenter work and materials. 764 Marcy Avenue
- Ackley, John
  Meat and provision dealer. 419 DeKalb Avenue near Franklin Avenue
- Acme Stationery, 1892
  Stationery and paper/"Manufacturers of pads, tablets, envelopes and fine box papers". corner of N. 9th & Wythe Ave
- Acme Steel Company, 1930
  Steel. 219 36th Street
- Acme Stove Co., 1937
  Gas ranges repaired and reconditioned. 2391 Pitkin Avenue
- Adams Coal Co., Inc., 1933
  Coal merchant. Gowanus Canal at Third Street
- Adams, Otto, 1895
  Hardware, house, furnishing, goods, paints and oils; roofing, stoves and furnaces. Fourth Avenue
- Adams, R.W. & Co., 1867, 1876
  Lumber dealers. Van Brunt St., Near Hamilton Avenue / Bonded yard, foot [of] 25th Street
- Adams, W.R. & Co., 1898
  Lumber dealers. Van Brunt and Bowne Streets Near Hamiltion Ferry
- Adelman, Dave, 1940
  Electrical appliances. 367 Pearl Street
- Adelphi Academy, 1878
- Adelphi Conservatory of Music, 1900
  School. 426 Carlton Avenue
- Adikes, J. & T., 1855
  Farm & Garden Seeds. Two stores: cor. Fulton and Ray Sts., and Division Street / Jamaica, NY
- Adlard, R., 1881
  Locks and keys fitted, carpentering, painting, and bronzing; repairing of all kinds. 690 Myrtle Av.
- Aetna Insurance Company, 1865, 1882, 1910
- Agar, H.Y. & D., 1935
  Real estate, insurance, mortgage loans, appraisals, realty managers. 9 Greene Ave at Fulton Street
- Ahearn & McNeil, 1895
  Dry dock / Shipwrights, caulkers, and sparmakers / tugs and barge builders. Foot of 26th street
- Ahn's Art Corporation, 1991
  Silk screen printing. 56 Box Street 11222
- Akerly, H., 1875
  Carpenter and builder. 87 North 5th Street Bet 2nd & 3rd Streets
- Al's Repair Shop, 1934
  Electrical contractor specializing in vacuum cleaner repairs and parts. 2386 Nostrand Avenue near Ave J
- Al's Service Station
  Gasoline etc.. 538 Vanderbilt Ave cor. Pacific St.
- Albert Pipe Supply Company, 1930
  Pipe supplies. Berry and North 13th street
- Albohn, Louis, 1895
  Painting, paperhanging and kalsomining. 167 Cooper St. [?]
- Aldridge & Garrison, 1860
  House furnishing. 357 Fulton Street, opposite City Hall
- Alexander Bros.
  General contactors. 2040 East 61st street
- Alexander & Ellis, 1923
  Lumber dealer. Cor. Kent avenue and Hewes Street
- Alfiery, Cesare, 1897
  Bottle dealer. 260 Fourth Avenue, in rear
- Alford, E.V. & Co., 1894
  Butchers tools. 152-154 Flushing Avenue bet. Clinton and Vanderbilt Avenues
- Allard Real Estate, 1924
  Real estate. 1321 Foster Avenue
- Allen, D.'s Sons Rope Company, 1912, 1913
  386 Third Avenue
- Allen, George, 1881
  Livery stable. 350 Court Street, cor. Union
- Allen, R.L., 1869
  Manufacturer of agricultural implements. Cor. Plymouth & Jay Street
- Allen, William T., 1893, 1898
  Boarding and livery stables. Nos. 20,22,24 and 26 Bainbridge Street
- Allied Chimney and Furnace Cleaning Co., 1947
  Chimney and furnace cleaning. 1706 East 45th Street
- Almond, T.R., 1891
  Patentee and manufacturer of the Almond Drill chuck and Almond patent coupling. 83 & 85 Washington Street
- Alpine Lumber Co., Inc., 1932
  Lumber merchant. 5th Ave, Corner 64th st
- Alyea, J. & P., 1877
  Carpenters and builders. 119 Fourth Place bet. Court and Smith Sts.
- American Auto Motor Locking Device Co., 1910
  Manufacturers of the automobile starting crank. 141-143 Stockholm Street
- American Carpet Cleaning Works and Storage Warehouses, 1913
  Carpet cleaning and storage. 159-161 & 163 25th Street / 200 & 202 24th Street
- American Electric & Acetylene Welding Co., 1929
  Engineers and contractors. 1852 Decatur Street (bet. Cypress & Myrtle Aves)
- American-Israeli Lighthouse, 1962
  Organization for rehabilitation of blind. Brooklyn chapter. 395 Ocean Avenue
- American Jewish Congress
  Brooklyn Women's Division, Coney Island Chapter. [president] 4006 Highland Avenue
- American Legion, 1950
  Philippines Post No. 1164, Kings County, Department of New York. 33 Sands St
- American Manufacturing Company, 1916, 1921
  Cordage. Noble and West Streets
- American News Company, The, 1900
  Newsdealers, booksellers and stationers. 39 & 41 Chambers Street
- American Safety Razor Corporation, 1927
- American Stamping Co., 1893
- American Surety Company of New York, The, 1898
  Financial. 367-373 Fulton Street
- American Thermos Bottle Company, 1908
  31 Washington Street
- Amity Baptist Church Inc., 1921
  Church. 172-4 Washington Street
- Anacreonte, Joseph A., 1946
  Real estate. 268 Flatbush Ave
- Anchor Cap & Closure Corporation, 1920
  Manufacturers of caps and machinery for vacuum and airtight sealing of tumblers, jars, and bottles. Pearl & Prospect Sts.
- Anderson, A., 1864, 1866, 1872
  Cemetery supplies. cor. Hicks and Baltic Streets; foot of Court Street; Leonard Street, near Hamilton Avenue
- Anderson, Adolph, 1932
  Painter and art decorator. 1295 Rogers Avenue
- Anderson, Robert, 1889
  Carpenter and builder. corner Gates and Marcy Avenues
- Anderson, Robert G. / Anderson's, 1868, 1878
  Confectionery and bakery. 250 Fulton Street corner of Clinton Street; 262 Fulton and 2&4 Clinton Sts
- Andresen & Blatt Folding Bed Co., The, 1890
  274, 276 & 278 Leonard St.; 87 Devoe cor. Leonard St
- Anson, John, 1894, 1908
  Hardware and ship chandlery. 53 Hamilton Ave
- Antom Plumbing & Heating Co.
  Plumbing and heating. 275 Nassau Boulevard, Garden City South, NY
- Apel, G.E. Sunshine, 1904
  Stoves, ranges and furnaces; hot water and steam heaters. 575 Fourth Ave
- Appelgate, Charles E., 1883
  Florist. 13 Putnam Ave
- Archer, T.F. Co., 1910
  Auctioneer. 451 Fulton Street Corner Bergen Avenue
- Architectural Iron Works, 1898
  240-246 N.10th St., near Union Avenue
- Arensberg, L. & Co., 1897
  Wholesale tobacconists. 143 Myrtle Avenue
- Arkay Shoe Co., Inc., 1918
  Shoe Manufacturing. Orange and Fulton Streets
- Armored Service Corporation, 1932
  57 Willoughby Street
- Armour & Company, 1907
  Atlanic and Snediker Aves
- Armour Packing Company, 1898
  Meat packing. 197 and 199 Fort Greene Place
- Armstrong & Blacklin, 1867, 1870, 1876
  Ornamental furnishing warehouse, plumbing, gas fitting, ranges and furnaces repaired, hose and hose pipes. 273 Court, corner Union Street
- Armstrong, James, 1878, 1883
  Plumbers, gas and steam fitters; Ornamental furnishings. 348 Court corner of Union Street and 409 Myrtle Avenue near Clinton Avenue; 349 Court Street near Union
- Armstrong, M.A. & Anson, 1867, 1873
  Hardware. 38 Hamilton Avenue and 6 President Street; 41 Hamilton Avenue and 10 President Street
- Arnold, J.H., 1878
  Manufacturer of stencil plates, burning brands, steel stamps, etc.. 49 Fulton St. bet. Pearl and Cliff
- Arnowitz, L., 1914
  Painter and decorator; painters' supplies and wallpaper; general contractor. 2379 Myrtle Ave (formerly 295 Knickerbocker Ave)
- Arnzen, Henry
  Watchmaker.
- Arnzen, Oliver, 1884
  Watchmaker and jeweler. 107 Broadway
- Aronson, Wm. B., 1888, 1889
  Glass dealer; glazer. 820, 809 Myrtle Avenue
- Arrow, House of Incorporated, The, 1940
  Automotive parts. 828-830 Bedford Avenue
- Arrow Office Supplies Company, 1942
  Office supplies. 20 West 22nd Street New York NY
- Arthur's Livery & Sale Stable, 1860, 1864
  11 Bergen Street
- Arthur's Service Station
  Gasoline etc.. 101 DeKalb Avenue cor. Navy St.
- Ash, Sam, Inc., 1960
  Music store. 236 Utica Avenue
- Ashton, John M., 1888
  House sign and decorative painter. Benson Avenue, Bath Beach
- Ashton, John Jr., 1905
  Carpenter and builder. Shops at 1325 Fulton Street and 204 Decatur Street
- Aspell & Co., 1881
  Wholesale grocer. 189 Columbia Street (Brooklyn branch)
- Atkin, John H., 1870
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. Fifth Avenue near 9th Street
- Atlantic Ave Improvement Committee of Brooklyn and Queens, 1926
  160 Jamaica Avenue
- Atlantic Avenue Subway League of Brooklyn and Queens, 1940
  9511 78th Street, Ozone Park
- Atlantic Dock Company, 1894
  Wharfage. No. 1 North Pier, Atlantic Dock, adjoining Hamilton Ferry
- Atlantic Fire Insurance Company of Brooklyn, 1865, 1866
  172, 173, 174 Atlantic Street
- Atlantic Pacific Manufacturing Corp, 1921
  124-128 Atlantic Ave through to 121-125 Pacific Street
- Atlas Savings & Loan Association, 1946
  689 Fifth Avenue
- Attix & Co. Fashionable Hatters, 1878
  340 Fulton Street, cor. Court Street
- Attletwed, C., 1899
  Shipwright, caulker, sparmaker and ship joiner. Foot 25th Street
- Auer, John and Sons, Inc., 1929
  Builder. 640-648 Lexington Avenue
- Auerbach, Charles, 1865
  French boot and shoe maker. 66 Court Street
- Austin, Nichols & Co., 1929
  Wholesale grocer. Kent Ave and N. 3rd Street
- Automatic Bank Punch Co., The, 1896
  83 Washington Street
- Avery, Thomas C., 1892
  Coppersmith and plumber. 725 and 727 Third Ave
- Avila & Barker, 1879
  Decorator.
- Ayers, George L., 1878
  Real estate agent and appraiser. 105 Flatbush Avenue
- B. and H. High Grade Slip Covers and Upholstery Shop, 1940
  Upholstery. 1318 Broadway near Ralph Ave
- B and L Press, 1944
  Printers. 2924 West 22nd Street
- B. & S. Stove Company, 1938, 1940
  Gas range and stove dealer. 1491, 1492 East New York Avenue
- Backman, George, 1976
  Building repairs. 2036 East 55th Street
- Backstrom, Albert, 1938
  Plumbing and heating. 2136 Flatbush Avenue near Quentin Road
- Bacon & Co., 1898
  Wholesale coal. Reid Avenue, corner Dekalb
- Baerenklau & Company, Inc., 1939
  Insulation and heating. 740 Jamaica Avenue
- Baier, F.A. & Son, 1897
  Soda and seltzer water, lager and root beer / Packing boxes, crates, etc.. 26, 28, 30 Guernsey and 469, 471, 473 Lorimer Streets
- Bailey & Hyland, 1808
  Marble cutters. corner Court St. and Fourth Place
- Bailey, James, 1864
  Embroidery and lace. 290 Fulton Street
- Bainbridge & Taylor, 1904
  Electricians and locksmiths. 411 Gates Avenue
- Bainbridge, W.P., 1897
  Electricians and locksmiths. 332 Gates Avenue
- Baisley, John, 1863
  Undertaker. No. 34 Court Street, west side of City Hall
- Baker,C.H., 1895
  Carpenter and builder. 87 Fort Green [sic] Place
- Baker, D.L., Inc., 1938
  Real estate. 254 Kings Highway
- Baker Congressional Campaign Committee, 1906
  Political committee. 544 Carlton Avenue (formerly 329 Franklin Avenue)
- Baker, E.I. Lorette, 1833
  House, sign and fresco painter and paper hanger. 444 Myrtle Avenue
- Baker, George & Sons, 1910
  Shoe Maker. 647 & 649 Lexington Ave.
- Baker, James M., 1890
  Painter. 256 Fifth Avenue
- Baldwin the Clothier, 1870, 1876, 1877, 1879
  380 and 382 Fulton Street corner of Smith Street
- Baldwin, J.A. & C.H., 1882
  Furniture, bedding, etc.. 46 & 48 Fourth Street
- Ball & Quimby, 1891
  Grates, ranges, heaters and furnaces. Successors to D.S. Quimby. 8 Henry Street, near Fulton
- Ballay, Constant, 1872
  Liquor store. 339 South Third Street, near Tenth
- Bamber, Issac, 1864
  House and sign painter. corner of South Seventh and Third Streets
- Bamber & Jansen, 1867, 1872, 1885
  House and sign painters and paper hangers. 87, 101, 127 Broadway
- Bank of the Manhattan Company, 1945
  26 Court Street
- Banta, H.B., 1881
  Carpenter and builder. 25 & 27 Bergen Street
- Baris, J.C. Lumber Co., Inc., 1920, 1930
  Lumber. Wrigley Terminal, Metropolitan & Woodward Avenues
- Barnard, J.T., 1881
  Lawyer. 346 Fulton St., cor. Boerum, Room No. 2, Long Island Savings Bank Building
- Barnes, E.W. & Co., 1873
  Lumber dealer. Columbia and Baltic Streets
- Barnes, G.W., 1895, 1909
  Mason and plasterer. 870, 881 Myrtle Ave bet. Marcy and Tompkins Aves.
- Barnes, Vincent, 1882
  Stoves, range, and furnaces; House furnishing goods etc.. Great Neck, Long Island
- Barney, John, 1879
  Stone work. cor. Bond and Carroll Streets
- Barnie, Alex. Jr., 1887
  Carpenter and builder. 253 Raymond Street near Fulton St.
- Barnie, Alexander, 1866
  Carpenter and builder. 367 Bridge Street, near Fulton Avenue
- Barnum, T.W., 1865
  Undertaker. Successor to N. Burrill. 132 Pierrepont Street
- Barrel, M., 1903
  Glass dealer. 89 Greenpoint Avenue
- Barret, P.T.'s, 1894
  Horseshoer. 488, 489 Clermont Avenue
- Barron's Textbook Exchange, 1960
  Bookstore. "Everything for the New Student." 35-39 Hillel Place; 35-37-39 Germania Place
- Barter, John W., 1872
  Plumber and gas fitter. 376 Atlantic Avenue, near Bond Street
- Bartlett & Greene, 1880
  106, 107 Wall Street, New York NY
- Bartow, Wm. E., 1889
  Carpenter and builder. 124 N. Elliott Place, opp. 14th Reg't Armory
- Bassett, Walter S., 1876
  Plumber and gas fitter. 788 Fulton Street, bet. Adelphi St. & Clermont Ave.
- Batterman, W., 1894
  Carpeting and furniture. 665 to 671 Broadway
- Bauer, C.J., 1900
  Meat market. 298 Bond Street near Sackett Street
- Bay View Heights Land Co., 1914
  16 Court Street
- Beame, Abraham D., 1967
  Politician. 70 Wall Street New York NY
- Beard & Kimpland, 1878
  Timber dealer. Corner of Hamilton Avenue and Clinton Street
- Beards, Edward, 1906
  Flooring importers. 856 Broadway, bet. Park and Lewis Aves.
- Beattie & McQuilkin, 1880
  Marble works. 366 Bedford Avenue, bet. Park and Myrtle Aves
- Beavan, E., 1879
  Fresco painting and decorative paper hanging. 19 Gates Avenue, corner of Vanderbilt Avenue
- Beavan, J., 1878, 1882
  Manufacturer of fine furs and dealer in hats and caps. 475, 501 Fulton Street
- Beavan, Wm. W., 1886
  Interior decoration. 19 Gates Avenue, corner of Vanderbilt Avenue
- Bechtold & Co., 1913
  Optician. 230 Livingston Street
- Beck, Benedict J., 1897
  Carriage manufacturer. 95 South Fifth Street, Near Bedford Ave.
- Becker, A., 1890
  Printer and stationer. 282 Graham Ave
- Becker, A.C., 1888
- Becker, George, 1900
  Merchant tailor. 604 Grand St bet. Lorimer and Leonard Sts.
- Becker, V., 1860, 1875
  Plumber and gas fitter. 213, 260 Grand Street, between 6th and 7th Sts., branch office, 1041 Broadway
- Beckmann, F., 1890
  Wood turner. 95 Gwinett Street bet. Harrison and Marcy Aves.
- Bedell, J.W., 1881
  Carpenter and builder. 205 Marcy Avenue
- Bedell, Wm. M., 1890
  Hay, straw and feed dealer. 10 Bushwick Avenue
- Bedford Branch YMCA, 1929
  1115-1125 Bedford Avenue
- Beer, Louis Sons, 1940
  Real estate. 166 Montague Street
- Beers & Resseguie, 1878
  Lumber dealer. Yard: cor. Washington & Flushing Aves / Steam Planing & Saw Mill, Grand Av. nr. Flushing Av.
- Behr, H., 1879
  Dealer in stoves, ranges, heaters etc.. 628 Third Avenue, bet. 17th & 18th Sts.
- Belknap, E.S., McSherry & Moran Co., 1907
  Industrial manufacturers. 5 & 7 Ainslie Street
- Bell Auto Service, 1925
  Motor livery. 1331 59th Street
- Bell, Harry W., 1899
  Fireproof material. Washington Avenue and Taylor Street
- Belle, Propeller, 1881
  Towing. foot of Baltic Street
- Bender, A.C., 1870
  Manufacturer of brewers pitch, sealing wax, and varnish. 15 Cook Street near Bushwick Ave
- Benjamin, B. & Bro., 1886
  Manufacturers of and dealers in cord, twine, rope, etc.. 24 Ten Eyck Street
- Benjamin, N., 1884
  Roofer. 341 N. 2nd St. bet Union Ave and Lorimer St.
- Bennett & Becker, 1876
  Tea merchant, coffee roasters and wholesale grocers. 10 Fulton Street
- Bennett, Geo. W. & E., 1881
  Shirt maker. 336 Fulton Street
- Bennett, John, 1882, 1883
  Undertaker. 155 Division Avenue
- Bennett & Longworth, 1863
  Undertaker. South 7th, cor. 3rd St.
- Bennett, William, 1917
  Hay, straw, grain and feed dealer. 76 Bushwick Avenue, corner Powers Street
- Benson, Hevlyn Dirck, 1939
  Historian. 23 Halsey Street
- Benson Park Civic Association, 1932
  Civic Association. 2104 73rd Street
- Benson Theatre, 1972
  Theatre. 20th Avenue and 86th Street
- Bentley, A., Mme., 1878, 1883
- Bentley, T., 1876
  Importer of fine millinery goods. 428 Fulton Street
- Bentzen, John J., 1888
  Mason and builder. Residence, 346 Bergen Street, yard, 232 State Street
- Berg, Jacob, 1944
  Foreign language advertising. 410 Eastern Parkway
- Bergen, J.V.B. [John Van Brunt Bergen], 1897, 1898
  Hardware and house furnishing goods. 1310 Third Avenue corner 56th Street
- Bergen, N.J., 1880
  Hay and straw dealer. Barges Bedford, Pilgrim, Cromwell & Union, Pier 1, Wallabout
- Berkoff, M.S. Co., Inc., 1961
  Hardware. 1400-04 Coney Island Avenue
- Bernhardt Bros., Inc., 1944
  Sanitary and janitors' supplies. 395 Atlantic Avenue
- Bernheim, Alfred, 1896
  Money changing and sending. 646 Broadway
- Berns, George H., 1872
  Milk dealer. 19 Hicks Street near Fulton
- Berri, William('s Sons), 1865, 1881, 1898
  Carpeting, oil cloths, etc.. 180 Fulton Avenue; 522, 524, 526, 528 Fulton Street
- Berriman Junior High School No. 64, 1956
  829 Belmont Avenue
- Berry Box Company, Inc.
  376 Vernon Avenue
- Berry & Williams, 1867
  House, sign and ornamental painters. 128 South Seventh Street
- Bertsch, Peter, 1890
  Painting and Japanning. 464, 466, 468, 470, 472, & 476 Broadway, cor. Penn St.
- Best Value Homes Corporation, 1928
  391 Fulton Street
- Beth Elohim, Congregation, 1947
  Women's Auxiliary. Eighth Avenue and Garfield Place
- Beth Emeth, Temple, of Flatbush, 1947, 1953
  83 Marlborough Road at Church Avenue
- Beth Jacob Hebrew School, 1960
  575 Bedford Avenue
- Beverly Shoe Shop, The, 1918
  Shoe store. Kings Highway (formerly 1050 Flatbush Avenue)
- Beyer, John A., 1882
  Mills and elevator; manufacturer of axle grease. Washington Avenue foot of Taylor Street
- Bieg, Henry, 1878, 1897
  Steam pressed drain pipes amd chimney top works. 361 Flushing Ave. and 56 to 64 Wallabout St.; Sewer drain pipe and chimney top work. 46 to 66 Wallabout Street
- Biffi's Reliable Roofing, 1907
  Contractor, roofing and repairs. 339 Flatbush Ave., near Park Place
- Biglow & Co, 1865, 1868
  Furs, hats and straw goods. 185 Fulton Street
- Bihl, William, 1896, 1900
  Sawing and turning mill, moulding and planing. 516, 576 Hamilton Ave., near Third Ave.
- Billin & Son, 1866
  Carpenters and builders. cor. DeKalb and DeBevoise Street
- Billott, John, 1889
  Carpenter. 366 Hicks Street, near Amity
- Bindrim, Julius, 1881, 1882, 1885
  Stone yard. cor. of Wythe Ave. and Hewes St.; cor. of Bedford Ave. and Rutledge Street; Flushing Ave., bet. Spencer and Walworth Sts.
- Binns, James, 1869
  Iron and brass foundry. Walworth Street, between Park and Flushing Avenues
- Birkett, J., 1871, 1877
  Plumber, steam and gas fitter. 68 Myrtle Ave. and 169 Cloumbia St.
- Birkett, James W. Manufacturing Co., The, 1895, 1896
  Brass and iron goods; Engineers and contractors. 351 and 353 Jay Street
- Birkett, John & Co., 1898, 1899
  Engineers and contractors. 386 Jay Street
- Bischoff, Henry W., 1892
  Boarding and livery stables. 944 Bedford Ave., bet. Willoughby and DeKalb Aves.
- Bishop, E.H., 1870
  House furnishings. 191 Flatbush Ave. and 616 Pacific St., near 5th Ave.
- Bishop, G.W., 1881
  Locksmilth. cor. St. James Place and Fulton St.
- Bishop, Howard W., 1907
  Electrician, locksmith and bellhanger. 1228 Bedford Avenue
- Bishop, McCormick & Bishop
  Car sales [?]. 1221 Bedford Avenue at Halsey Street
- Bishop, William's Sons, 1897
  Plumbers, coppersmiths and steam fitters. 724 3rd Ave (Brooklyn branch)
- Blacklin, J.J., 1878
  Plumber and gas fitter. 348 Court Street, corner of Union.
- Blakeney, Geo. W., 1894
  Saddle and harness maker. 602, 633 Vanderbilt Ave., near St. Marks
- Bland, J.B. and J.W., 1870
  Furniture, bedding, etc.. 156 & 158 Myrtle Avenue bet. Prince and Gold Streets
- Blank Bros., 1882
  Manufacturers of brushes. 474 Broadway near Walton St.
- Blank, George, 1914
  Real estate and mortgage loans. 244 Bleecker St corner Knickerbocker Ave
- Bleecker Shoes, 1959
  Shoe store. 5651 Myrtle Ave.
- Bleiberg Plumbing Supplies, Inc., 1935
  Plumbing supplies. 329-31 Sutter Avenue
- Bliss & Davis, 1867
  Masons and builders. 104 Harrison Street
- Bliss, E.W. Co., 1901, 1905, 1929
  Manufacturers of presses, dies, and special machinery. Adams and Plymouth Streets
- Bliss, James, 1869, 1871
  Mason and vault builder. 104 Harrison Street
- Block,Samuel Company, 1925
  Insurance. 149 Remsen Street
- Blohm,Robert T., 1895
  Ship chandlery, builders' hardware. corner 25th St and 3rd Ave
- Bloomingdale, C.A., 1899
  Commission merchant--hay, straw, and grain. Palmers Dock, Kent Ave and North 9th Street
- Bloor, H.P., 1867
  Glass stainer. 364 Atlantic Street bet. Hoyt and Bond Streets
- Bloor & Tuckhorn, 1883
  Stained glass decorators. 380 Atlantic Avenue, near Bond St.